Department of Special Collections, Hesburgh Libraries of Notre Dame
American Colonial Currency Collection
- Massachusetts Currency 1736MassachusettsOctober 14, 1736, MA 1736; ;
  - Two shillings, six pence497 497, 599; A. Winthrop, William Dudley, Elisha Cooke and John Quincy; 105 x 136
    This 2s6d half crown note includes the original date of October 14, 1713, in the body of the text, with the redatings: 1714, 1718, 1719, 1721, 1723, 1725, 1727 and 1727 along the bottom right margin. Also, just below the main text the redatings of 1733 and 1735 have been lost due to holes in the paper, only an initial 17 of the date 1733 is visible. On the far right end of that line the numbers 36 remain, this is from the final redating on this note, namely 1736. The plate that produced this issue was later reused once again in 1740. The 1740 date was added below the central frame, just to the right of the crown on the royal seal. Fortunately, that portion of this specimen is intact and 1740 date is not present, thus we can conclude the specimen was printed for one of the two emissions in 1736.The central text reads: [THIS INDENTE]D Bill of Two shillings [and six pence due from t]he Province of ye Massachysets [B]ay in New England to the Possessor thereof shall be in [V]alue equal to Money And shall be accordingly [a]ccepted by the Treasurr & Receivers subordinate to [hi]m in all Publick payment and for any Stock at [any time] in ye Treasury Bo[st]on Octobr ye f[ourteenth 1713] By Order of [the Great and General Court or Assembly]. The text is framed in a six-sided border, consisting of two right angles on the right side and a three-sided border on the left. Only a small fragment of the upper margin indent design remains on the top right. The signatures are quite similar to those on a one-shilling Massachusetts note of 1735 illustrated in Eric Newman, The Early Paper Money of America, fifth ed., 2008, p. 191.Serial Number: quite faded, possibly 497